我叫艾莉丝
My name is Alice.
我曾为安布雷拉公司
I worked for the Umbrella Corporation
这个世上最大最强的公司效命
the largest and most powerful commercial entity in the world.
我担任保安主任
I was head of security
负责保护“蜂巢”
at a secret high-tech facility called The Hive
这个发展实验性生化武器的地下高科技实验室
a giant underground laboratory developing experimentalviral weaponry.
但意外发生
But there was an incident.
病毒扩散，大家都死了
The virus escaped and everybody died.
问题是 他们并没有完全死掉
Trouble was they didn't stay dead.
T病毒控制了他们的身体
The T-virus reanimated their bodies.
但我活了下来
But I survived.
我和另一个人，环保份子麦特
Myself and one other an environmentalist named Matt.
我们逃出来时，却被安布雷拉的科学家捉住
When we emerged, we were seized by Umbrella scientists.
麦特和我被迫分开
Matt and I were separated.
他在突变，我要把他纳入奈密司计划
He's mutating. I want him in the Nemesis Program.
麦特！
Matt!
送她到拉昆市的机构，组一队人
Take her to the Raccoon City facility and assemble the team.
重开“蜂巢”
We're reopening The Hive.
我要知道下面发生什么事
I want to know what went on down there.
我们以为灾难已经过去
We thought we'd survived the horror.
但我们错了
But we were wrong.
《生化危机：启示录》
这是拉昆第7台，现在报告气象
You're watching Raccoon 7. Now the weather, with Terri Morales.
现在是上午6：10，气温已高达33度
It's 6:10 in the a.m. And already the temperature has reached　a massive 92 degrees
这股空前的热浪将继续发威
as this unprecedented heat wave continues.
拉昆市晴天，吹西风
Clear skies in Raccoon City and a light breeze coming in from the west.
好消息，粉尘值只有0.7
And as a special bonus just for you, we have a pollen count of 0. 7.
这个值可是同期最低
That's a record low for this time of year.
花粉热、气喘病患可以安心了
Good news for all you hay fever and asthma sufferers.
看来今天会是个晴朗的好日子
All in all, it looks like it's gonna be another beautiful day.
别转台，广告后是大众喜爱的假日热点
Stay with us. After the break,we're gonna look at your favorite holiday hot spots.
(蜂巢入口  拉昆市地下)
先遣小组前进
Advance team, proceed.
长官.
Sir.
天哪！
Holy shit.
(黑门大桥  拉昆市主要联外桥梁)
抱歉，夫人，出了点意外
Excuse us, ma'am. There's been an incident.
抱歉，先生，出了点意外
Excuse us, sir. There's been an incident.
情况有多糟？
How bad is it?
你得跟我们走
You must come with us
我要带我女儿一起走
I must get my daughter.
已经有人在处理了
It's taken care of.
等等，你干嘛？
What are you doing?
你们不明白，她去上学了
You don't understand. She's left for school.
(拉昆市初中)
这是UG7，完成撤离
This is U-Gamma 7, evacuation complete
不过G12小组失去联系
but we just lost contact with Gamma 12.
(13小时后)
12小队请求支援市政厅
Unit 12 calling for immediate backup at city hall.
目前原因不明
Still no explanation for this wave of unexplained killings
莫名杀戮持续横扫本市
that is sweeping across the city.
犯罪行为继续扩散
A deadly crime spree with no end.
我们需要支援！
Backup, we need backup now!
跟范伦婷说的一样
Just like Valentine told us
休假员警立刻向执勤单位报到
Off-duty law enforcement personnel, report for duty immediately.
快帮忙！这家伙疯了！
Give us a hand over here, this guy's insane!
是范伦婷！
It's Valentine.
别开枪！
Hold your fire.
范伦婷！
Valentine!
他们受到感染了
They're infected.
快帮我拉开这个丑女！
Somebody get this ugly bitch off of me!
我说过
I told you.
要射脑袋
Shoot for the head.
拜托！快拉住她！
Please, somebody get her.
不！别开枪！
No! Don't shoot! Don't
我要离开城里，我建议你也这么做
I'm leaving town. I suggest you do the same.
据报安布雷拉公司派出武装警卫
We've received reports of Umbrella Corporation
(艾莉丝计划开始启动)
(活死人横行)
请依序通过检查站
Move in an orderly fashion to security checkpoints.
本市已遭污染，军队已全面封锁
The city is completely contained. Troops have sealed all exits.
唯一的出口就是这座桥
The only way out is this bridge.
全体市民必须通过身体扫瞄
All citizens must pass through medical scanning.
长官！
Sir!
你最好过来看看
You better take a look at this.
家族成员必须一起通过检查站
Family members must pass through security checkpoints together.
请依序前进，请勿奔跑
Please proceed in an orderly fashion. Do not run.
他没问题，让他过
He's clean. Let him pass.
下一个！
Next!
不要推挤！
No pushing, please.
排好队！
Keep in line.
直升机D，新命令
Chopper Delta, new orders.
直接飞往黑门大桥
Proceed directly to Ravens Gate Bridge.
那里极需支援
Reinforcements urgently needed.
知道了，基地，马上到
Copy that, base. On our way.
打开！
Get it.
不！走开！
No! Get off!
走开！
Get away!
不！住手！
No! Stop! Get off!
不！退后！
No! Get back!
有市民有麻烦！
Civilian in trouble.
三点钟方向，快下去
Three o'clock. Go down.
不行！我们有任务！
I can't. We have our orders.
不！退后！
No! Get back! No!
他们会杀了她的！快下去！
They're gonna kill her! Take us down now!
她是老百姓，我们有任务在身
She's a civilian. We have orders.
去他的任务！
Fuck orders!
尼寇莱！绑住我！
Nicholai, tie me off.
退后！退后！
Get back! No!
等等！
Wait!
就是现在！
Now!
让我们下去！快！
Take us down! Down, now!
你没事吧？
Hey. Hey, you okay?
别站在边缘，过来我这儿
Step away from the edge. Come over to me.
没事了
Everything's okay.
不，会有事的
No, it's not.
我看过被咬过的人的样子
I've seen what happens to you once you've been bitten.
我们能帮你
We can help you.
没有活路了
There's no going back.
不！
No!
让开！
Move!
培顿！
Peyton!
范伦婷！
Peyton! Valentine. Hey, Valentine.
让开！警察！
Move! Police! Move!
让她过来！
Let her through.
很高兴你来，我们需要帮忙
Glad you're here. We could use the help.
他心脏不好
He has a weak heart.
别靠近他！
Get away from him!
大家退后！
Everybody, stand back!
爸爸！
Daddy!
别靠近他！
Get away from him!
把她拉开！
Get her away from him! It's okay.
拉开她！把她拉走！
Get away from him!Get her away from him!
爸爸！
Daddy!
没关系，有我在
It's okay, I got you.
快把他拉开！
Get him off! Get him off me!
退后！
Move aside!
病毒已经到达闸门了
It's here. It's reached the gate.
你怎么还在这？你该趁早走的
Why are you here? You should've got out while you had the chance.
这些是我们的同胞，吉儿
These are our people, Jill.
关闭闸门
Close them.
长官？
Sir?
关闭闸门！
Seal the gates.
我们的人还在里面
Our men are still out there
快关！
Just do it.
本区是生化危害区
This is a biohazard quarantine area.
由于有感染危险，你们不能离开
Due to risk of infection, you cannot be allowed to leave the city.
这是在搞什么？
What the fuck is going on here?
我们已采取所有适当措施
All appropriate measures are being taken.
状况已受到控制
The situation is under control.
各位请回家
Please return to your homes.
你逃不掉的！
You won't get away with this!
你们有五秒钟的时间回头
You have five seconds to turn around and return to the city.
快点！
Do it.
上级已授权可使用武器驱离
Use of live ammunition has been authorized.
五
Five.
他们不能对百姓开枪的
They can't shoot people!
四
four!
他们不会开枪的
They won't fire.
三
Three.
- 快叫他们回来！ - 二
- Get them back! - Two.
快走！一
Move! One.
快走！
Move
大家快走！
Everybody, clear out!
K小队与R小队到1区会合
Kilo and Romeo squads, rendezvous at sector 01
歼灭敌人
and secure against enemy.
手榴弹！
Grenade! Grenade!
3到7小队全数撤离
Squads three to seven are on full retreat.
不，行动失败，无法控制
No, sir. Suppression measures have failed. We can't contain it.
传染速度出人意料的快
The infection is spreading faster than anyone anticipated.
艾胥佛博士！
Dr. Ashford.
你不是该坐上直升机了？
Shouldn't you be on the chopper?
我不走
I'm not going.
我奉命撤离你和其它科学家
I was instructed to get you and the other scientists out of the hot zone.
你是安布雷拉公司的重要资产
You're too important to Umbrella to be at risk.
我没有我女儿不走
I'm not leaving without my daughter.
很对不起，但本市已经封锁
I'm sorry, truly. But the city is sealed.
她可能没死，但我们找不到她
She may have survived the crash, but we couldn't find her anywhere.
就算她还活着，我也不能让她走
Even if she were still alive, I couldn't let her out.
感染的危险太大了，请你谅解
The risk of infection is too great. You must understand.
你做你该做的事，我要留下
You do what you have to do.I'm staying.
(第五级密码登入)
(密码取消)
(请求远端遥控)
(拒绝登入)
(登入成功)
(搜寻安琪拉艾胥佛)
(在拉昆市国中寻获)
一定还有人活着
There has to be someone left alive.
快啊
Come on.
(搜寻中)
(寻获)
不！
No!
麦特！
Matt!
送她到拉昆市的机构
Take her to the Raccoon City facility.
把她隔离，仔细观察
I want her quarantined. Close observation.
准备注射
Prepare her for exposure.
提升剂量
Up the dosage.
快点！
Just do it.
(搜寻中)
(寻获)
我们得休息会儿
Let's stop somewhere.
我们去哪儿？
Where are we going?
这他妈究竟怎么回事？
What the fuck is going on?
他们朝人群中开枪
They are shooting people
都是些无辜的老百姓
innocent people.
你俩应该做点什么
Why don't you something
你们可是警察啊！
you're the police
进去
Inside
找掩护
Let's get under cover.
你们给我出去！
You have to get out.
这是我的地方
This is my place.
我躲在这里
I'm hiding here.
这里很大，我们可以一起躲
It's big enough for all of us.
少说废话
Don't tell me
别激动！
Okay, just cool it.
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
至于你，别激动
And, you, take it easy.
不用枪，它也会让你死在这
It's been a way to get yourself killed here, without get yourself shot.
你是吉儿·范伦婷，对吧？
Jill Valentine, right?
还记得我吗？
Remember me?
我报导过你几件案子
I covered some of your cases.
在你停职之前
Before your suspension.
泰莉·莫瑞斯，第7台的
Terri More Alice, Raccoon 7.
已经见过你干的所有事了
I've seen all your work.
兴趣而已
I found.
并非如此
Not really.
你现在播天气预报了，对吧？
You did weaponry there, right?
这是培顿·威尔斯中士
This is Sergeant Peyton Wells.
你手上拿着什么？
What's that you got there?
我的艾美奖
My Emmy.
如果我们有人能幸存的话
That's if any of us make it out of here.
警方对那些玩意有何评论？
So does the Raccoon City Police Department have any comment on what those things are?
我主判决
The lord judgment
看吧，我将把恶灵带给世人
Behold, I will bring evil upon these people.
如果他们不再领悟我的圣言
For they have my packened onto my words.
不再敬仰我主，但我拒绝了
Nor on my lord. But I rejected it.
醒来吧，远离尘世
Awake, leave the dwelling dust.
死者将与活人同行
The dead shall walk amongst the living.
并给予他们惩罚
And bring the damnation onto them.
出色的演讲
That's quite a speech.
非常精彩，可以作为最后一个镜头
That was great. That's gonna make the final cut.
那是什么？
What was that?
没什么
That's nothing.
你还好吧？
Are you all right?
你做什么？
What are you doing?
怎么回事？
What's wrong?
那是我妹妹，她生病了
It's my sister. She's not well.
也许我能帮忙
Maybe I can help. No.
不用了
No.
让开
Out of my way.
给我出去！
Just get out.
你在喂养她
You're feeding her?
你真恶心！
You're sick.
别管我们
Just leave us alone.
不！
No!
我要离开这里！
I'm getting out of here. Hey.
不要！
Hey! Hey, no!
我的老天！
Oh, my God!
快来帮忙！
Hey, help us!
快啊！
Come on!
快进去！
Get it in there!
那是什么鬼东西？
What the hell was that?
在那里！
There!
天啊！
Jesus.
那是什么玩意？
What the fuck is that thing?
你干嘛？快回来！
What are you doing? Get back here.
培顿！泰莉！
Peyton.Terri.
培顿！
Peyton.
我知道
I know.
那个爱尔兰学生
The Irish student.
不，他是苏格兰人
No he's Scottish.
什么？
What?
我算过有三只
I count three of them.
它们困住我们了
They got us boxed in.
我们该怎么办？
What are we gonna do?
带她出去
Do you get her out?
我们走
Let's go.
老天爷
Jesus.
我们需要更多弹药
We're gonna need more ammo.
我没子弹了
I'm out.
我也没子弹了
Shit. I'm out.
让开！
Move.
你是谁啊？
Who the fuck are you?
疯狂大赛车！
GTA, motherfucker!
好耶！
Oh, yeah!
十分！
Ten points!
长的不错啊，小妞
He's damn looking good, baby.
找别人去吧
Ask him to find out who's second air
尤里！你没事吧？
Yuri. You okay?
吃炸弹吧！
Bite this.
你没事吧？
You okay?
没事
Yeah. Yeah.
撤退！
Pull back!
往这边走！
This way.
这是奥利维拉
This is Olivera.
我们遇袭，请派直升机撤离
We've been overrun. Request immediate chopper evac.
我们他妈的在这里做什么
What the fuck are we doing here.
喂
Hello!
难道
Am I
难道只有我一个人在担心我们何时会变成僵尸？
Am I the only one who's not thinking we're not the grave yard people?
好吧，有什么计划？
OK. What's the point?
留着命
Stay alive.
就这样？就这样？
That's it? That's it?!
就这样
Hem. That's it.
我们得找个地方暂时落脚
We need to find somewhere to stop for a moment.
不，我不认为这可行
I don't think that's a good idea.
可能会有更多的怪物
There might be more of those things.
要是有的话，我们早遇上了
If there were more, we'd have seen them by now.
你知道它们是什么？
You know what they are?
安布雷拉地下实验室的生化武器
They're bio-weapons from Umbrella labs beneath the city.
你怎么这么清楚安布雷拉？
How come you know so much about Umbrella?
我曾为他们效过力
I used to work for them.
该死！
Damn it.
等等！
Hold it.
你想干嘛？
What do you think you're doing?
他受了伤，感染正在扩大
He's wounded. The infection's spreading.
我没事
I'm fine.
你现在就该解决他
You should take care of him now.
再等下去就更难解决
It'll be more difficult later.
你知道的
You know that.
不
No.
到那时，我自会处理
If it comes to that I'll take care of it myself.
随你便
As you wish.
这无关个人
It's nothing personal.
但1个小时内，也许是两个小时，你就死定了
But in an hour, maybe two you'll be dead.
之后没多久，你就会变成它们那样
And moments later, you'll become one of them.
你会危及到朋友，试图杀害他们
You'll endanger your friends, try to kill them
可能还会成功
probably succeed.
对不起
I'm sorry.
事实就是如此
That's just the way it is.
救命！
Help me!
他们人太多了！
There's too many of them.
快离开这里！往这边走！
Let's get out of here. This way!
T病毒感染已达危急程度
Sir, T-virus infection has reached critical levels.
(感染程度危急)
这是个完美的机会
This is a perfect opportunity.
务必记录所有数据资料
Ensure all data streams are recorded.
启动奈密司计划
Activate Nemesis Program now.
(启动复仇邪神)
(镇静剂-静脉注射)
(肌肉松弛剂-自动停止)
阿尔法呼叫基地，这是阿尔法呼叫基地
Alfa ding to base. This is Alfa ding to base.
回话，基地
Come in, base.
嘿！集中精力，战士
Hey, pay attention, solider.
阿尔法呼叫基地，这是阿尔法呼叫基地
Alfa ding to base. This Alfa ding to base.
回话，基地
Come in, base.
你保持注意力，好吗
You stay focus. Alright?
是，长官
Yes, sir.
阿尔法呼叫基地，这是阿尔法
Alfa ding to base. This Alfa
为什么不回应我们？
Yes, yes. Why don't they respond go to us?
为什么不让我们撤退，嗯？
Why don't they evac us, eh?
我不知道
I don't know.
为什么他们先送我们来这里？
Why do they send us here in the first place?
我们没有任何机会
We never stood a chance.
我们没有任何把握
We We're not sure for this.
等等！
Wait!
听
listen.
嘿！这里啊！我们在这里！嘿！过来！我们在这里！
Hey! Here! We're down here!Hey! Come! We're here!
他们要去哪？
Where are they going?
他们要在那里降落，快扶尤里去
They're landing there. Let's get Yuri!
来吧，尤里，我们要出去了
Come on, Yuri. We're getting out.
我们好好安置你的，来吧
We'll get you fixed up. Come.
撑着点，我们就快到了
Hold on, Yuri. We're almost there.
不！别走！
No. No! Don't leave!
不！快下来！我们来了！
Down here! We're coming!
他们投东西到医院，你看到吗？
They dropped something on hosptial，did you see them？
也许是无线电
Maybe a radio,One that works.
照顾尤里
Take Yuri.
撑着点，尤里
Hold on, Yuri.
尼寇莱，放我下来
Nicholai, put me down.
好，在这休息
Okay, rest here.
这是什么？
What is this?
看来像是 武器箱
Looks like weapon cases.
我们不需要武器，我们要撤离
We don't need weapons. We need evacuation!
这些不是给我们的
These weren't meant for us.
我有的是子弹！
Plenty to go around.
别开枪！
Don't shoot!
我是神射手
I got the power.
谢了！我欠你一次！
Thank you! Owe you one, man.
妈呀，外面还比较安全咧
Shit! Maybe I was safer outside.
把枪从我脸上移开
Get them guns out of my damn face.
拜托，你看看
Motherfucker, please. Look
我的家伙才正点
my shit is custom.
那是什么玩意？
What the fuck is that?
靠！
Shit!
你死定了，大怪胎
You're going down, you son of a bitch!
靠！
Fuck.
成防卫队形，撂倒他
Deploy defensive formation. Take him down.
你们疯了
You fuckers is crazy.
那个大怪物手上拿着火箭筒呢
Look at that guy, got a rocket launcher.
什么情况？
What do we have?
一队武装人类
A dozen armed men.
组织严密
Well organized.
我很惊讶竟然有人还能活着
I'm surprised there's anyone left.
他们是S.T.A.R.S.
They're S.T.A.R.S.
特种战术援救小组
Special Tactics and Rescue Squad.
他们都是高手
They're the best.
开火！
Fire!
撤退！
Back! Fall back!
看看他们有多行吧
Let's see how good they really are.
变更指令
Altering protocols.
(杀光特种战术援救小组)
不堪一击！
S.T.A.R.S.
妈呀
Oh, shit.
我投降
Respect.
(武装平民　威胁：很低)
(非战斗人员　威胁：零)
狗日的
It's the white motherfucker.
你没权利操蛋
You have no right to do shit.
狗娘养的
You're one son of a bitch.
操，我最屌
Oh, shit. I'm a bad motherfucker.
噢，我最屌
Oh, I'm a bad motherfucker.
我得离开这鬼地方
Oh, I'll get the fuck out of here
你在看什么?
What're you staring at?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
你怎么进的保护伞公司？
What made you one of the Umbrella?
混口饭吃
I was gonna make a living.
你的身手真不错
Those were some pretty slick moves back there.
我很行，但还没有你行
I'm good，but I'm not that good.
你该庆幸这点
You should be thankful for that.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
他们对我动了手脚
They did something to me.
我已经不太觉得自己是人类了
I barely feel human anymore.
我们继续前进
We should keep moving.
趁这声音还没引来怪物之前
Before the sound attracts anything.
继续走
Keep moving.
喂？
Hello?
我还以为你们永远不会接电话呢
God, I thought you'd never answer.
你是谁？
Who is this?
我能帮你们逃出拉昆市
I can get you out of the city.
你们四个
All four of you.
但首先我们得做个约定
But first we have to come to an arrangement.
你们同意吗？
Are you ready to make a deal?
我们有选择吗？
Do we have a choice?
没有，想活过今晚就得答应
Not if you want to live past tonight, no.
他是艾胥佛博士，他负责
His name is Dr. Ashford and he
负责安布雷拉的基因病毒研究部
Runs the genetics and viral research division of Umbrella Corporation.
他要我们干嘛？
What's he want with us?
他女儿安琪拉被困在城里
His daughter, Angela, is trapped in the city.
安布雷拉公司原本应该要撤离她
Umbrella was to evac her
但行动失败，她目前躲在学校
but she didn't make it.She's hiding out in her school.
找到她，他就会帮我们逃离此地
We find her, he'll help us escape the perimeter.
想都别想
No fucking deal.
我们会找栋门坚墙固的建筑
We find the building with the thickest walls and doors
固守在里面
and we barricade ourselves in.
等待救援
Sit tight, wait for help.
不会有人来救援的
There won't be any help.
博士说安布雷拉知道感染已失控
Umbrella knows they can't contain the infection.
所以等天一亮
So at sunrise this morning
拉昆市就会被彻底消毒
Raccoon City will be completely sanitized.
什么叫彻底消毒？
What do you mean by "sanitized"?
一个精密的战略性核子武器
A precision tactical nuclear device.
威力多大？
What yield?
相当于五千吨炸药
Five kilotons.
太扯了
Fuck me. Stupid.
那是什么意思？
What does that mean?
那可以摧毁感染的状况
It means it'll destroy the infection
还有所有的证据
and all evidence of it.
这太过份了
It's bullshit. It's bullshit!
他们不可能盖过去
No fucking way would they get away with that!
电视新闻会报导一切
It would be all over the fucking news!
用藉口掩饰
Cover-up.
藉口已经准备好了
Cover-up's already prepared.
核电厂的反应堆发生状况
A meltdown at the nuclear power plant.
一场悲剧性的意外
A tragic accident.
安布雷拉不可能有办法掩饰一切
Not even Umbrella is capable of this.
不可能？培顿，你当时在现场
Not capable? Peyton, you were there.
就在桥头
At the bridge.
你很清楚他们会无所不用其极
You know exactly how far Umbrella will go.
那我们现在该怎么办？
So, what do we do now, huh?
我想我们天亮前要离开
I think we should be out of here by sunrise.
(搜寻中)
(寻获)
万一根本没出路呢？
What if there is no way out
他还变态的到处监视我们
and he's watching us on these cameras
就像一种恶心的游戏？
like this is some kind of sick game?
怎么回事？
What is it? What's going on?
等等
Wait.
天亮可不会等我们
Sunrise ain't gonna wait.
不，下面有东西
No.There's something down there.
哪里？
Where?
那里
There.
我没看到什么东西
I don't see anything.
没看到并不代表没有
That doesn't alter the fact that there is something down there.
我受够这一切了！
I'm getting sick of this bullshit!
培顿
Peyton!
不！
No!
他找到另外两个特种部队队员
He's located another two S.T.A.R.S. Members.
(目标:范伦婷 培顿)
复仇邪神，快跑
Nemesis! Run! Just go!
快逃啊！
Just go!
主要目标已确认
Primary target is identified.
各位，我们等待的就是这一刻
Gentlemen, this is what we've been waiting for.
2点18分27秒确认
Confirm at 2: 18 and 27 seconds.
复仇邪神已全面启动
The Nemesis Program is now fully activated.
(垃圾投弃口)
(战斗中止)
你朋友的事我很抱歉
Look, I'm I'm sorry about your friend.
我们快去学校找这个小孩吧
Let's just get to the school and find this kid.
我的老天！
This bite
不，培顿！
No，Peyton!
伤口一直血流不止
it won't stop bleeding.
他们怎么会没看到我们？
Why didn't they see us?
什么？
What?
直升机啊，我们就在医院前面
The chopper. We were right there in the street in front of the hospital.
他们怎么会看不见我们？
How could they not see us?
他们看到了
They saw us.
这话什么意思？
What do you mean?
我们是资产，可牺牲的资产
We're assets, Nicholai.Expendable assets.
所以我们被牺牲掉了
And we've just been expended.
停车！
Stop!
我不是活死人
I'm not one of those things.
记得我吧？
Hey, remember me?
你看，我没被咬到
Look, I haven't been bitten or anything. Look.
上车吧
Climb aboard.
我叫杰佛森韦德
Lloyd Jefferson Wade.
你们可以叫我阿杰
You can call me L.J. On account of the informal situation.
(寻获安琪拉艾胥佛)
我们得分开来找
We're gonna have to split up to search this place.
不要!
Forget it!
不要！我不要自己一个人去
Forget it! I'm not going out there by myself.
我可以跟你一起去找
I can go with you.
你搜一楼
You, take the first floor.
你搜二楼
You, take the second.
我搜地下室
I'll take the basement.
我没有开过枪
I've never shot a gun before.
这很简单
There's nothing to it.
瞄准，射击，重复
Point, pull, repeat.
设法射他们的头部
Try to hit them in the head.
瞄准，射击，重复
Point, pull, repeat.
我看到你了，死骷髅
I see you, mother Oh, shit!
噢，埃尔维斯！
Oh, Elvis!
你也接到电话了？
So did you get the call as well?
什么？
What?
你们是来找那女孩的？
You're here for the girl?
对，是，是为那女孩
Oh, yeah, yeah. The girl.
艾胥佛博士没说他还找了别人
Dr. Ashford didn't say he made a deal with someone else.
我想我们算是伙伴了
I guess we're partners.
该死
Shit.
安琪拉，不会有事的
Angela? It's gonna be okay.
不用害怕
There's no need to be afraid.
我们会带你回家的
We're gonna take you home.
我的老天！
Oh, my God.Help me!
泰莉？
Terri?
你帮不了她的
You can't help her.
太晚了
Not now.
我看到他们把她吃了
I've seen what they do.
你是安琪拉？
Are you Angela?
对，我们得趁他们回来前赶快走
Yes，We should hurry before they come back.
拿着这个
Hold this.
你叫安琪拉·艾胥佛？
Angela Ashford, huh?
小女孩怎么叫这么成熟的名字？
That's a pretty grown-up name for a little girl.
我不是小女孩,而且
I'm not a little girl. Besides
我朋友都叫我安琪
all my friends call me Angie.
安琪？我喜欢
Angie, huh? I like that.
那些东西在这里
Those things are in here.
他们动作慢，我们可以绕过去
It's okay, honey. They're slow. We can run around them.
不，不是他们
No.Not them.
是它们
Them.
退后
Get back.
别乱动
Stay.
我想你可能需要帮忙
Thought you might need a hand.
你是安布雷拉公司的人？
You work for Umbrella?
以前是
Used to.
直到他们把我们扔在这里等死
Until they left us for dead in this place.
我现在算是自由工作者了
Now I consider myself freelance.
尼寇莱中士为你效劳
Sergeant Nicholai Genovev, at your service.
快跑！
Come on!
等等！
Wait!
安琪！
Angie!
去救那个女孩！
Save the girl!
我来对付这只死母狗！
I've got this bitch.
糟糕
Oh, shit.
从现在起，要紧跟着我
From now on, stay right beside me.
门被堵住了
It's blocked.
现在该怎么办？
What do we do now?
在这等着
Wait here.
小心看着, 好吗？
Eyes, Okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
你们认识？
You two know each other?
她受过感染
She's infected.
而且是高度感染
She's infected on a massive level.
你怎么知道？
How can you know that?
因为她也一样
Because she is too.
你也被感染了？
You're infected?
你打算什么时候才告诉我们？
When were you gonna tell us that?
我看看
Let me see.
不要
No.
你知道我不会伤害你的
You know I'm not gonna hurt you.
让我看看
Let me see.
这是解毒剂，可以治愈T病毒
It's the antivirus, the cure to the T-virus.
有解毒剂？
There's a cure?
你怎么会有？
How did you get this?
我爸爸
My daddy.
我爸爸帮我做的
My daddy made it for me.
他瘫痪了，有一天我也会瘫痪
He's sick. And someday, I'll get sick too.
他只是想阻止那种情况发生
He just wanted to stop that.
我小的时候
When I was little
只能拄着拐杖走路
I had to walk on crutches.
他们说我再也不会变好了，只会变得更糟
They said I'd never get better, just worse.
他发现了让我变强壮的方法
He found a way to make me stronger.
T病毒
The T-virus.
后来他们夺走了他的发明
Then they took the invention away from him.
滚出我家
Get out of my house!
他不是坏人
He's not a bad man.
他无意造成这一切
He didn't mean for any of this.
没关系
It's okay.
别开枪！他没问题
Don't shoot! He's cool.
他跟博士达成了协议，跟你一样
He made a deal with Dr. Doom, same as you.
你们有多少人？
How many of you guys are there?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
尼寇莱
Nicholai.
你什么时候被咬的？
When were you bitten?
三小时前
Three hours ago.
搞什么？
What the?
你今天走运了
It's your lucky day.
你该说你被咬了，我跟你一起耶
Should have told me you got bit. I'm hanging with you and shit.
让我跟我女儿说话
Let me speak to my daughter.
首先，你得告诉我们怎么出去
First, you tell us how we're getting out.
有一架直升机已经在待命
There's a helicopter already being prepped.
它将47分钟后起飞
It takes off in 47 minutes.
那是引爆核弹前的最后一个架次
It'll be the last transport to leave Raccoon City before they detonate.
我想这架直升机不是来接我们的
I take it this helicopter isn't laid out just for us.
它有别的任务，但它没人看守
No. It has another purpose, but it'll be lightly guarded.
地点在哪？
Where's the evac site?
我现在能跟女儿说话了吧？
May I speak to my daughter now?
爸爸？
Daddy?
嘿，甜心，你还好吧？
Hey, sweetheart. Are you all right?
我什么时候能看到你？
When can I see you?
快了
Soon.
这些人很快就会带你来见我
These people will bring you to see me. I'll see you very soon.
叫那个姐姐来听
Put the lady back on.
我们该去哪里？
Where do we have to go?
直升机停在市政厅
The helicopter will be at city hall.
我建议你们动作快点
I suggest you make haste.
(连接失败)
电脑, 真靠不住
Computers, so unreliable.
跟人一样
Just like people.
你真以为我不知道？
You really thought I didn't know?
你帮我注射什么？
So, what are you injecting me with?
解毒剂
The antivirus.
T病毒重新活化死去的细胞
The T-virus reanimates dead cells.
让死人活过来
Basically, bringing the dead to life.
或让活人产生无法控制的突变
Or in a living human, it can cause uncontrollable mutation.
它让她得以再度行走
Or it can help her walk again
只要继续以这玩意控制病毒
if the virus is kept in check with this.
安琪也受到了感染？
Angie's infected?
对，细胞的成长足以让她再生
Yes.The cellular growth is enough to regenerate her
却不会让她更进一步突变
but not enough to cause mutation.
他们让你也受到T病毒感染？
And they infected you with the T-virus as well?
对
Yeah.
不过别担心，我没有传染危险
But don't worry. I'm not contagious.
拿去
Here.
录下整个故事，我会让它物有所用
Tape the story. I'll see that it gets put to good use.
我叫艾莉丝
My name is Alice.
我曾为安布雷拉公司
I worked for the Umbrella Corporation
世上最大最强的公司效命
the largest and most powerful commercial entity in the world.
我担任保安主任
I was head of security
负责保护“蜂巢”
at a secret high-tech facility called The Hive
这个发展实验性生化武器的地下高科技实验室
a giant underground laboratory developing experimental viral weaponry.
走吧
Let's go.
你漏了一个
You missed one.
我们得快点
We have to hurry.
没问题的，有的是时间
We're okay. We have time.
不，我们得快点
No! We have to hurry.
妈呀，我们偷的是他的直升机
Holy shit! We stealing his ride!
起飞
Take off.
我说，起飞！
I said, take off!
急什么？
What's the rush?
我们一直在等你
We've been expecting you.
周边已肃清
Perimeter secure.
所有区域都已封锁
All sectors locked down.
安琪！
Angie!
爸爸！
Daddy!
我就知道你不会丢下我
I knew you wouldn't leave me.
当然，永远不会
No. Never.
放下武器
Discard primary weaponry.
你们两个展现出无比的潜力
The two of you showed such promise
但我们得看你们动手
but we had to see you in action.
用你们的必杀技
And most impressive you've been.
你们就像兄妹
You're like brother and sister.
身手无比快速、强壮、敏捷
Heightened speed, strength, agility.
还有相同的杀手本能
the same killer instincts.
两个同时进行的研究
Parallel strands of research.
现在，我们将知道谁比较强了
And now Now we'll discover which is superior.
跟他决斗
Fight him.
不
No.
跟他决斗，否则他们就死定了
Fight him, or they die.
你凭什么认为我会在乎？
What makes you think I care?
爸爸，不！
Daddy! Daddy, no.
不！
No.
他原本是公司的重要资产
He was a valuable asset to the corporation.
我根本不在乎这些人
I don't even care about these people.
动手吧
Begin.
他在突变，把他纳入奈密司计划
He's mutating. I want him in the Nemesis Program.
麦特！
Matt!
细胞结构瓦解
Cellular structure breaking down.
T病毒出现基因突变
T-virus is manifesting itself in a genetic mutation.
我们发现相同的细胞再生情况
We're seeing similar cellular regeneration.
对不起
I'm sorry.
麦特，对不起
Oh, Matt. I'm so sorry.
解决他
Finish him.
我叫你解决他
I said, finish him.
不
No.
你还不明白你对我有多重要吗？
Don't you understand how important you are to me?
那怪物虽然很强
That creature is one thing
但你与T病毒却结合了
but you somehow you bonded with the T-virus on a cellular level.
你适应并改变了它
You adapted it, changed it.
你成了无敌超人
You became magnificent.
我成了怪物
I became a freak.
不
No.
你不是突变，你是进化了
You're not mutation. You're evolution.
想想有了我帮忙，你会变得多强？
With my help, just imagine what you can achieve.
那他呢？
What about him?
演化自有其尽头
Evolution has its dead ends.
快解决这一切
Now, finish this.
让他死个痛快
Put him out of his misery
然后跟我走
and come with me.
不
No.
我对你真失望
You're such a disappointment to me.
充满力量却不用，真浪费
All that strength，but no will to use it. What a waste.
准备起飞
Prepare for takeoff.
听我号令开始彻底消毒拉昆市
Sanitation of Raccoon City to commence on my mark.
杀了她！
Kill her.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
快升空！
Get us airborne.
我是最高指挥肯恩
This is Cain. Priority overload.
开始发射程序
Initiate launch proceedings.
倒数五分钟后引爆
Detonation set at T-minus 5 minutes.
安琪，趴下！
Angie, get down!
为什么还不起飞？
Why haven't we taken off?
因为我比较习惯开凯迪拉克
Because I usually drive a Cadillac.
投降，否则格杀勿论
Surrender, or we open fire.
放下武器！
Drop it.
艾莉丝！
Alice!
放下武器投降！
Drop your weapon and surrender.
快把这玩意开上天！
Let's get this thing in the air!
你得站起来
You have to get up.
麦特
Matt
来吧，我们得走了
Come on, we have to go.
我们得走了，来
We have to go. Come on.
来吧
Come on.
起来！
Get up!
你别指望我会下跪求你
If you expect me to beg, I will not.
等等
Wait.
杀了我并不能解决事情
Killing me won't put things right.
没错！
No
但这至少是个开始！
but it's a start.
你不会有事吧？
Are you going to be all right?
大家抓稳了！
Hang on to something!
我们要坠机了！
We're going down!
(拉昆市郊亚克雷山区)
(两小时后)
UG9报告基地
U-Gamma 9 to base.
确认已找到坠机地点
Confirmation.We've located the crash site.
快派医疗小组过来
Fetch the medical team.
其他人呢？
What about the others?
没有发现其他尸体
no other bodies found, sir.
拉昆市的意外有了初步报导
We have unconfirmed reports of disaster at Raccoon City.
本台获得这些骇人的画面
These shocking images just in.
一场神秘瘟疫或病毒感染导致局势失控
A mysterious plague or viral outbreak has run rampant
安布雷拉公司害死无辜平民
Implicating Umbrella Corporation in deaths of innocent citizens.
这是拉昆第七台的泰莉所拍摄的
This tape, work of former Raccoon 7 anchorwoman Terri Morales.
新证据推翻先前的报导
New evidence now discredits earlier reports
显示那只是一个恶作剧
Nothing more than sick joke.
假影带完全被推翻
Fake videotape totally discredited.
那只是一个恶作剧
Nothing more than a big hoax.
拿拉昆市稍早的悲剧来开玩笑
Playing on the very real tragedy which overwhelmed Raccoon City this week.
核电厂反应炉发生重大意外
The reactor at the nuclear power station went critical.
这是自1986年，前苏联切尔诺贝利事件后最大的核子灾难
The worst atomic disaster since the Russian Chernobyl incident in 1986.
州长特别致意安布雷拉公司
The state governor personally thanked the Umbrella Corporation
感谢其迅速处理善后
for their swift action
恶作剧的吉儿和卡洛斯
The perpetrators of the hoax, Jill Valentine and Carlos Olivera
目前已被警方留置侦讯
now being sought for questioning by the police.
(拉昆市意外发生三周后)
(安布雷拉医学研究机构)
艾莉丝 艾莉丝
Alice Alice
艾莉丝
Alice
醒醒！
wake up!
你听得见我吗？
Can you hear me?
你听得懂我说的话吗？
Do you understand what I'm saying?
很好
Good.
开始清洗程序
Begin the purging process.
她复原的速度惊人
Her recovery's remarkable.
还有她的力量，不论生理或心理
And her powers, both physical and mental
都以等比级数的程度增加
are developing at a geometric rate.
哪 哪里？
Where Where?
你在哪里吗？
Where are you?
哪里？
Where?
你很安全，来吧
You're safe，Come on.
很好，就是这样
That's it.There we are.
你知道那是什么吗？
Do you know what that is?
这是一支笔，你看
It's a pen，You see?
你试试
You try.
很好
That's it.
笔
Pen.
看着我
Look at me.
你还记得什么？
Can you remember anything?
你记得你的名字吗？
You remember your name?
我的名字？
My name?
我要她接受全天候的观察
I want her under 24-hour observation.
名字
My name.
今天结束前还要彻底检测血液
A complete set of blood work.
还有化学及电解质分析
Chemical and electrolyte analysis by the end of the day.
我的名字
My name.
博士!
Sir!
还要做反射作用检测
Advanced reflex testing is a priority.
我的名字
My name.
监测她的电子脉冲
Monitor electrical impulses.
博士
Sir.
博士！
Sir！
什么事？
What is it?
我的名字叫
My name
艾莉丝
is Alice
而我也记得所有的事
And I remember everything.
这是控制中心，请立刻支援
This is central. Request immediate backup.
请求强力支援
Maximum response.
谢谢，我们会接手处理
Thank you, gentlemen. We'll take over from here.
这是谁授权的？
On whose authority?
最高机密
Classified.
第六级授权
Level six authorization.
抱歉
Sorry, sir.
让他们走
Let them go.
你能回来真好
Good to have you back.
你还好吧？
Are you all right?
艾莉丝计划启动
Program Alice activated.
他们对你做了什么？
What did they do to you?
本产品由安布雷拉公司出品
This is a product of the Umbrella Corporation.
我们热爱生命
Our business is life itself.
请注意副作用
Some side effects may occur.
未完，待续 请期待生化危机3
to be continue Resident Evil Ⅲ